<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScrollView</string>
    <string name="textview"><b>How do I develop my ideas in a paragraph?</b> \n\n
    <p>Often, the body paragraph demonstrates and develops your topic sentence through an ordered, logical progression of ideas. There are a number of useful techniques for expanding on topic sentences and developing your ideas in a paragraph. Illustration in a paragraph supports a general statement by means of examples, details, or relevant quotations (with your comments).\n

        In Harry’s world fate works not only through powers and objects such as prophecies, the Sorting Hat, wands, and the Goblet of Fire, but also through people. Repeatedly, other characters decide Harry’s future for him, depriving him of freedom and choice. For example, before his eleventh birthday, the Dursleys control Harry’s life, keeping from him knowledge of his past and understanding of his identity (Sorcerer’s 49). In Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets, Dobby repeatedly assumes control over events by intercepting Ron’s and Hermione’s letters during the summer; by sealing the barrier to Platform 93⁄4, causing Harry to miss the Hogwarts Express; and by sending a Bludger after Harry in a Quidditch match, breaking his wrist. Yet again, in Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, many adults intercede while attempting to protect Harry from perceived danger, as Snape observes: “Everyone from the Minister of Magic downward has been trying to keep famous Harry Potter safe from Sirius Black” (284). All these characters, as enactors of fate, unknowingly drive Harry toward his destiny by attempting to control or to direct his life, while themselves controlled and directed by fate. \n

        —Julia Pond, “A Story of the Exceptional: Fate and Free Will in the Harry Potter Series” \n
        The definition paragraph does exactly what you would expect: it defines a term, often by drawing distinctions between the term and other related ones. The definition that you provide will often be specific to your subject area. Try to avoid perfunctory dictionary definitions that do not inform your analysis in a meaningful way.\n

        Our typology is built on three dimensions: internality, types of participants, and the degree of effective resistance. For our study, a civil war is any armed conflict that involves (a) military action internal to the metropole, (b) the active participation of the national government, and (c) effective resistance by both sides. With these criteria, we differentiate civil wars from other types of internal violent conflicts.\n

        —Melvin Small and J. David Singer, Resort to Arms: International and Civil Wars, 1816–1980
    </p>
    <p>The analysis or classification paragraph develops a topic by distinguishing its component parts and discussing each of these parts separately.\n

        Policies of privatisation should be considered as responses to several distinct pressures. First, privatisation is a response by the state to internal forces such as increasing fiscal problems (O’Connor, 1973). It provides a means of lessening the state’s fiscal responsibilities by encouraging the development of private alternatives which, theoretically at least, do not draw upon the state’s financial reserves. Second, the promotion of private sector activity is a response to pressures originating ‘outside’ the state apparatus. These include demands from people who see a large state bureaucracy as inefficient and wasteful, demands from business interests who claim that they can overcome these inefficiencies, and pressures from client groups who seek to reduce their dependency on the welfare state by having more control over the services on which they depend. Clearly, this variety of calls for privatisation means that it is not a process with a uniform outcome; there exists a correspondingly wide variety of forms of privatisation.\n

        —Adapted from Glenda Laws, “Privatisation and the Local Welfare State”\n

        A comparison or a contrast paragraph zeroes in on a key similarity or difference between, for instance, two sources, positions, or ideas. Decide whether to deal only with similarities or only with differences, or to cover both. Also, keep in mind that a single comparison can be spread out over two separate paragraphs. As the following topic sentence indicates, you should make your intention clear to readers from the outset.

        Evidence from industrialized countries suggests that compared with older men, older women more often experience functional impairments and activity limitations, have longer durations of disability, and spend proportionately more remaining years of life disabled.

        —Kathryn M. Yount, “Differences in Disability among Older Women in Egypt and Tunisia”

    </p>
    <p>The analysis or classification paragraph develops a topic by distinguishing its component parts and discussing each of these parts separately.\n

    The process paragraph involves a straightforward step-by-step description. Process description often follows a chronological sequence./n
    </p>
    </string>
</resources>